# Kenan Bölükbaşı

Keran Davidov

# Software Engineer, Game Developer & Designer, Architect

*	İSTANBUL - TURKEY
	KENANBOLUKBASI@GMAIL.COM
<b>②</b>	☑ KENANB.COM ☑ 6X13.COM
	Windows:
	♥ KENANBOLUKBASI
>	C KENANB C 6x13

# SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Software Engineer with in-depth knowledge in 3D scene description, surface representation and processing. Highly experienced in compiled languages, and low-level debugging. Highly experienced in project pipeline and tools development. Experienced in project management.

Previously: Game developer, and designer, Blender 3D specialist, Blender Foundation Certified Trainer. Theoretical and applied knowledge in design and media.

### PERSONAL DETAILS

CITIZENSHIP EU (Bulgarian), Turkish
DRIVER'S LICENCE B Class

### **EDUCATION**

2005 – 2017	Architecture (B.Arch.) Istanbul Technical University, ITU School of Architecture, İstanbul
2001 - 2005	<b>High School (Science and Math)</b> Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School, Bursa

## CONFERENCES & WORKSHOPS

## TALKS & LECTURES

2017

2017	ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
2016	Toxicity in Gaming: Negative Effects of Prioritizing Player Motivation in World Design ITU School of Architecture, Taşkışla, İstanbul
2014	<b>Prototyping &amp; Optimizing Game Asset Workflow</b> Blender Conference, Amsterdam
2014	Automated Sprite Rendering System in Blender Libre Graphics Meeting, Leipzig
2014	<b>Blender Python Programming Workshop</b> <i>BlendFX Studios, Leipzig</i>

Introduction to Modern Computer Graphics

#### PARTICIPATION

THE THE THE THE		
2021	SIGGRAPH Attendee, Virtual	
2021	<b>DigiPro and The Pipeline Conference</b> Attendee, Virtual	
2021	<b>CppCon</b> Attendee, Virtual	
2021	Game Developers Conference Attendee, Virtual	
2015	Game Developers Conference Europe Volunteer, Cologne	

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Weta Digital (WetaFX), Wellington Jan 2018 – [cont'd] Software Engineer

Software Engineer at Pipeline Department.

- Development and integration of various technologies for visual effects pipelines.
- Development of visual effects artist focused tools, developer focused tools and software libraries.

# 6x13 Games, İstanbul Jan 2015 – Dec 2017 Founder, Project Leader & Developer

Project leader. Game design and development. Graphic design and game asset creation. Prototyping, pipeline optimization.

- Game design, game & level editor development, project lead, graphics and user interface design of TWINIWT, the innovative, free to play symmetrical movement puzzle.
   Globally featured on both AppStore and Play Store.
- Project management & development of 1FPS GAME SERIES.
   4 mobile F2P games: 1FPS: INVADERS, 1FPS: VACUUM, 1FPS: FASTFOOD, 1FPS: GRAFFITI[WIP]
- Cocos2d-x based in-house cross-platform game framework.
- Design, development and artwork of WRECKJUMPER[WIP], forced-perspective sci-fi TBS with dynamic puzzle elements.
- Visualization module for an architectural research project (for evolutionary-algoritm driven facade generation) at ITU.
- $\bullet$  Development of Fossicker, open source asset prospector.
- Guest lecturer for M.Arch., M.Sc. in Design Computing courses and B.Arch. design studios at ITU.

# EKSERIYA STUDIOS, İSTANBUL AUG 2013 – JAN 2015 Graphics Department Lead & TD

Decision making on graphics technology and workflow. Tools and pipeline development. Prototyping. Asset shading, lighting.

- Asset pipeline automation system (import, lighting, rendering, compositing & atlas) for mobile RTS, SILICON WARS.
- Environment art and map editor for RIOT DEFENSE game.
- Pseudo 3D graphics R&D for FOOTBALL WIZARD game.

# FREELANCE, İSTANBUL

Jun 2011 - Feb 2014

### Visualization Artist

Archviz for various firms. Modeling & rendering of office furniture catalog of Bürosit as well as indoor visualizations.

# EFOR EVENTS & SIMMETRICO, BAKU AUG 2011 – SEP 2011 Assistant Site Manager

Construction site management of a large steel structure for the wedding event of Azerbaijani President's daughter, in a multinational (Italian, Turkish & Azerbaijani) environment.

#### EFOR EVENTS, İSTANBUL

JUL 2010 - APR 2013

# **Event Supervisor**

Workflow & stage manager. Major events: Windows 8 Turkey Launch, Kenan Doğulu concert, VIP trip to Czech Republic. Clients: Microsoft, TeliaSonera, Huawei, Volvo, Doğuş, Soyak.

## Aşçıoğlu İnşaat, İstanbul

SEP 2009 - Nov 2009

# Assistant Site Manager, Internship

Application supervision at Acıbadem Hospital building of Selenium Twins (BJK Süleyman Seba Complex) construction site.

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES & FRAMEWORKS

</> C / C++ </> **Pvthon** Common Lisp, Scheme 00000 </>> </> x86 Assembly </> **LLVM 1111** </> UNIX / Shell 00000 </> TeX / LATeX Systems </> Lua, HTML5

#### **DEVELOPMENT TOOLS & LIBRARIES**

99999 </> **Emacs Visual Studio** </> 0000 </> GCC, Clang, MSBuild 0000 </> GDB, LLDB </> Make, CMake **1111** </> Git Version Control System 00000 </> Doxygen, Org-Mode </> Xcode, Android Studio 

#### GRAPHICS & VFX SOFTWARE

00000 </> Blender 3D USD 00000 </> GIMP, Inkscape, ImageMagick 00000 </> </> AutoCAD, DraftSight 000 </> Houdini </> Maya

### OPERATING SYSTEMS

</> **GNU/Linux** 00000 </> Windows </> macOS

### SOFTWARE PROJECTS

#### 2021 **NOP Mode**

A code annotation and navigation system, designed to be supported by IDE and editor plugins. Aims to improve code navigation for reading code.

#### Twiniwt Mobile Game, 6x13 Games 2017

An innovative symmetrical movement puzzle. Globally featured on the AppStore Puzzle and Board categories, as well as Play Store Indie Highlights and Indie Corner. It works on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Written in C/C++, using Cocos2d-x.

#### 2016 1FPS Retro Game Series, 6x13 Games 4 games that work on all popular mobile and desktop platforms. Written in C++, using Cocos2d-x.

#### Fossicker, The Asset Prospector, 6x13 Games 2015 An asset generator that regexp over asset name to create relevant dummies. Powerful plugin system relies on CLOS and Context Oriented Programming.

#### Riot Game Map Editor, Ekseriya 2014

Map editor, importer/exporter that lets users both define and tile assets on a grid, export & raytrace the scene. Uses Blender Game Engine and Python.

#### Sprite Automation System, Ekseriya 2013

A system for automated game asset creation workflow. Uses Python, Blender3D (BPY) and Bash.

#### 2012

Common Lisp parser/reader and writer for IESNA LM-63 Photometry Standard files.

### COMMUNICATION SKILLS

#### ENGLISH

- Listening: C2 (Mastery)\* Reading: C2 (Mastery)\*
- Spoken Interaction: C2 (Mastery)\* Spoken Production: C2 (Mastery)\*
- Writing: C2 (Mastery)\*
- Prep Class Nilüfer Milli Piyango Anatolian High School Technical English Course - ITU Academic Essay Writing Course – ITU Research Paper Writing Course - ITU
- Lives and works in Wellington, New Zealand since 2018. Previously, VIP event supervision in various countries.

#### TURKISH

- · Native Speaker
- (\*) Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

#### Additional Information

Walking, Computer Science, Technology HOBBIES Blogging, Literature, Charcoal Drawing Free / Libre & Open Source Software, COMMUNITIES Blender Network, Lisp Game Development

